NumPy has a module for random sampling,
يحتوي NumPy على وحدة نمطية لأخذ العينات العشوائية،
that makes it really easy for us to simulate random events like coin flips and Python.
مما يجعل من السهل حقًا بالنسبة لنا محاكاة الأحداث العشوائية مثل تقلبات العملة وPython.
We're going to start with a simple example,
سنبدأ بمثال بسيط، وهو
simulating a single coin flip.
محاكاة صورة عملة واحدة.
For this, we'll use a function called randint.
لعمل ذلك، سنستخدم دالة تسمى randint.
This generates however many random integers,
على الرغم من أن ذلك يؤدي هذا إلى توليد العديد من الأعداد الصحيحة العشوائية،
we specify between a lower bound inclusive and upper bound exclusive.
فإننا نحدد بين الحد الأدنى الشامل والحد الأقصى الحصري.
We can use these integers to represent the outcomes of our events,
يمكننا استخدام هذه الأعداد الصحيحة لتمثيل نتائج أحداثنا،
like coin flips. Let's try this out.
مثل تقلبات العملة. لنجرب هذا.
We call randint from NumPy's random sampling module like this.
نقوم باستدعاء الوحدة النمطية لأخذ العينات العشوائية من NumPy مثل هذه.
Let's use zero to represent heads and one to represent tails.
دعونا نستخدم الصفر لتمثيل الرؤوس والواحد لتمثيل الذيول.
Let's make this function randomly produce zero or one.
دعونا نجعل هذه الدالة تنتج صفر أو واحد عشوائيًا.
The lower bound would be zero and the highest would be two, because it's exclusive.
سيكون الحد الأدنى صفرًا، وسيكون الأعلى اثنين، لأنه حصري.
Since the lower bound is zero,
نظرًا لأن الحد الأدنى هو الصفر،
this is actually the default.
فإن هذا هو الافتراضي بالفعل.
We don't need to include it.
لا نحتاج إلى تضمينه.
If we run the cell again and again,
إذا قمنا بتشغيل الخلية مرة بعد مرة،
we'll keep getting a random outcome of zero or one or,
فسنستمر في الحصول على نتيجة عشوائية للصفر أو الواحد،
we can specify a size to just give us more events.
أو يمكننا تحديد حجمًا ليمنحنا المزيد من الأحداث.
Cool. Now, we have the results of 10,000 random coin flips.
رائع. الآن، لدينا نتائج 1,0000 من تقلب العملة العشوائي.
The average of these outcomes produced here should be very close to 0.5,
يجب أن يكون متوسط هذه النتائج المنتجة هنا قريبًا جدًا من 0.5،
since right now there's an equal probability of getting a zero or a one.
حيث توجد الآن احتمالية التساوي للحصول على صفر أو واحد.
But what if we want to flip a biased coin,
ولكن ماذا لو أردنا أن نقلب عملة معدنية منحرفة،
that had a higher probability of landing on heads.
كان لها احتمالية أكبر للهبوط على الرؤوس.
There's actually another function for this called random.choice.
هناك بالفعل دالة أخرى لهذا تسمى random.choice.
This function works a little differently.
تعمل هذه الدالة بشكل مختلف قليلًا.
It randomly chooses a number of values from an array that you provide and you
تختار هذه الدالة عشوائيًا عددًا من القيم من صفيف تقوم بتوفيره،
can also give it a set of probabilities for each value in that array.
ويمكنك أيضًا توفير مجموعة من الاحتمالات لكل قيمة في هذا الصفيف.
Let's call random.choice and give it the array of the possible outcomes zero and one.
دعونا نستدعي random.choice ونعطيها مجموعة من النتائج المحتملة للصفر والواحد.
If we don't specify probabilities,
إذا لم نقم بتحديد الاحتمالات،
it gives us each value and an equal probability by default.
فإنها تعطينا كل قيمة واحتمالية تساوي بشكل افتراضي.
We can run this similar to the above example in this way.
يمكننا إجراء هذه المماثلة للمثال أعلاه بهذه الطريقة.
So the average is very close to 0.5 Again.
لذا فإن المتوسط قريب جدًا من 0.5 مرة أخرى.
To make this a biased coin,
لجعل هذه العملة منحازة،
we can specify the parameter p with an array of probabilities.
يمكننا تحديد المعلمة p مع صفيف من الاحتمالات.
Say 0.8 for heads and 0-2 for tails.
لنفترض 0.8 للرؤوس و0-2 للذيول.
Now, you can see that the mean is close to 0.2 which makes
الآن، يمكنك أن ترى أن المتوسط يقترب من 0.2 وهو أمر
sense because the zero or heads should be chosen 80% of the time.
منطقي لأنه يجب اختيار الصفر أو الرؤوس بنسبة 80% من الوقت.
You probably noticed that the mean values we get from
ربما تكون قد لاحظت أن القيم المتوسطة التي نحصل عليها من
these outcomes don't always reflect the true probabilities perfectly.
هذه النتائج لا تعكس دائمًا الاحتمالات الحقيقية تمامًا.
However, they do tend to reflect the true probability
ومع ذلك، فإنها تميل إلى عكس الاحتمال الحقيقي
more closely as we increase the number of flips.
بشكل أكثر قربًا كلما قمنا بزيادة عدد التقلبات.
You'll learn more about this later.
ستتعرف على المزيد عن ذلك لاحقًا.